

Kay Savage

Holistic Therapist – Reflexology, Indian Head Massage & other Complementary Therapies.

Wellbeing Therapist- Counselling, neuro-linguistic programming (NLP) and Coaching.

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012.

Email: info@healthcity.org.uk, Website: https://healthcity.org.uk/

Profile

10 years of experience of working in partnership with clients with complex needs: substance misuse/mental health/ex-offenders/learning disabilities/youths and adults. Including Drug Intervention Programme experience of referral-resettlement /licence sustainment/needs assessments/support plans/care packages, evaluating and developing care plans, risk/need assessments and managing challenging behaviour.

With a clear understanding of the need for and ability to deliver quality integrated services and proven experience of working within a multi-disciplinary team, capability to communicate confidently and effectively at all levels. Respond flexibly to the demands of the post as all as work as a member of a team. Make personal investment in the success of the project.

Education & Training

1990 - 1992 OND, Leisure Studies, Vauxhall College

1992 – 1994 HND, Business Information Technology, Thames Valley University

1994 – 1996 BSc Honours in Business Information Technology, Thames Valley University

1999 – 2000 Counselling Skills Practical, Merton College

2000 - 2001 Counselling Skills Theory, St Thames College

2003 Neuro Linguistic Programming Practitioner, PPD Learning

2010 Diploma in Reflexology, London School of Reflexology

2012 Diploma in Indian Head Massage, London School of Reflexology

2012 First Aid, London School of Reflexology

2012 Reflexology Diploma in Preconception, Pregnancy & Post Natal Care London School of

Reflexology

2012 First Degree Level Reiki, Reiki Academy London

2013 Reflexology Cancer and Palliative Care, City Literary Institute

2014 Cancer and Palliative Care, Pauls Cancer Support Centre

2015 Power Reflexology, London School of Reflexology

Employment

Aug 2015 - Present Alcohol & Drug Support Worker, CRI Newham

 Conduct Initial Assessments and devised Care Plans; managed a caseload of prescribing and non-prescribing clients. Liaise, Transfer and Advocate on behalf of clients, Accompany and facilitate Clients attending Medical Reviews, Titration and Re-titration, facilitate drug and alcohol tests. Facilitated SMART Group.

May - August 2015 Alcohol & Drug Support Worker, CRI Watford

 Conduct Initial Assessments and devised Care Plans; managed a caseload of prescribing and non-prescribing clients. Liaise, Transfer and Advocate on behalf of clients, Accompany and facilitate Clients attending Medical Reviews, Titration and Re-titration, facilitate drug and alcohol tests, delivered complementary therapy in the form of Reflexology and Indian Head Massage Therapy Treatments.

Apr – May 2015 CASS Alcohol Support Worker, West Kensington

Conducted Assessments and 1:1 Key Work Sessions, Managed a caseload
of Clients, Developed Recovery Care Plans, Liaised and Worked with
Partnership Services. Delivered Complementary Therapy in the form of
Reflexology and Indian Head Massage Treatments.

Nov 2014 to Present Volunteer Complementary Therapist Volunteer Paul Cancer Support Centre

 Delivering Home Therapy Treatments in the form of Reflexology and Indian Head Massage to Clients diagnosed with Cancer offering tailored made Palliative Care.

Jan to Apr 2015 Recovery and Engagement Support Worker, IHear Partnership, Hounslow

Co-Facilitate Opiate Support Workshop and Alcohol Abstinent Workshop
Conduct Initial Assessments and devise Care Plans; manage a caseload of
prescribing and non-prescribing clients. Liaise, Transfer and Advocate on
behalf of clients, Accompany and facilitate Clients attending Medical Reviews,
Ti-titration and Re-titration, facilitate drug and alcohol tests, deliver
complementary therapy in the form of Reflexology and Indian Head Massage
Therapy Treatments.

Oct 2014 to Jan 2015 Drug & Alcohol Support Prescribing Worker, Compass Enfield

 Conduct Initial Assessments and devise Care Plans; manage a caseload of prescribing and non-prescribing clients. Liaise, Transfer and Advocate on behalf of clients, Accompany and facilitate Clients attending Medical Reviews, Ti-titration and Re-titration, facilitate drug and alcohol tests, deliver complementary therapy in the form of Reflexology and Indian Head Massage Therapy Treatments.

Sep 2014 to February 2015 Lexham House, Residential Rehab – Part time

Joint and Lone Drug & Alcohol Support Worker role managing a team
Residents undergoing rehabilitation. Dispensing medication, take part in
activities with Clients i.e. attending leisure facilities, cooking food, providing
support, deliver complementary therapies treatments in the form of
Reflexology and Indian Head Massage, monitor visitors, phone calls.

July 2013 to Sep 2014 CRI Richmond DIP

 Undertaking Case Managing and Arrest Referrals at Walworth Police Station completing Triages and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health / substance misuse / homeless issues as a referral basis for clients using Class A and B drugs who wished to be signposted to specific treatment services available in the clinic and borough wide. Manage a case load. Facilitated Cannabis Group, delivered Complementary Therapy Workshop.

May - July 2013 Southwark DIP, Blenheim CDP

 Undertaking Case Managing and Arrest Referrals at Walworth Police Station completing Triages and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health / substance misuse / homeless issues as a referral basis for clients using Class A and B drugs who wished to be signposted to specific treatment services available in the clinic and borough wide. Manage a case load.

Mar - May 2013 Arrest Referral & Duty Court Worker, Harrow WDP

 Undertaking Arrest Referrals at Harrow Police Station and Court Duty at Hendon Magistrates Completing Triages and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health / substance misuse / homeless issues as a referral basis for clients using Class A and B drugs who wished to be signposted to specific treatment services available in the clinic and borough wide.

April 2013 CIPD Open Day, Wimbledon

- Invited as a Holistic Therapist, to participate in the event CIPD Open Day –
 conducted Complementary Therapy treatments in the form of Hand and Feet
 Reflexology, along with Indian Head Massage and Reiki.
- Due to the event being a successful, received a second invite from CIPD Open Day in October 2013.

Jan 2012 - Mar 2013 Group Worker CRI Ealing

- Co-Facilitate Induction and Core Support Groups for Clients placed on DRR
- Deliver Complementary Therapy Treatments in the form of Reflexology, Reiki and Indian Head Massage
- Conduct Triage, DRR and Risk Assessments as well as referring clients.
 Devise and reviewing Care Plans/treatment pathways to meet the identified need of DIP clients.
- Conduct 1:1 Key Working Sessions
- Completed Breach proceedings for non-attendance of individuals tested positive for substance use.
- Ensured completion of all forms relating to client in the form of care plans, TOPS, NDTMS

Dec 2012 – Jan 2013 DIP Worker WDP Croydon

 Undertaking Arrest Referrals at Croydon Police Station and Court Duty at Croydon Magistrates Completing Triages and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health / substance misuse / homeless issues as a referral basis for clients using Class A and B drugs who wished to be signposted to specific treatment services available in the clinic and borough wide.

Oct - Dec 2012 Duty Assessor, DASH St Anns' Hospital, Haringey

- Completing Triages and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health / substance misuse / homeless issues as a referral basis for clients using Class A and B drugs who wished to be signposted to specific treatment services available in the clinic and borough wide.
- Undertaking prescribing duties i.e. complete and adjust medication prescriptions
- Liaise with co-workers, in-house and external GPs and Psychiatrists, borough treatment centres, neighbouring treatment teams and Social Services.

- Identify and validate initial safeguarding issues e.g. contact with Children 16vrs and under.
- Provide initial and ongoing support for families and friends as well as referring to specific support networks.
- Maintaining contact on behalf of the co-workers when unavailable to meet with allocated clients ensuring continuous co-ordination of client care.
- Facilitated Needle Exchange Service.
- Undertaking UDS Drug and Breathalyser tests.
- Assist with on-site dispensing prescribed medication e.g. Methadone

Feb – Mar 2012 Smart CJS – Maidenhead, Berkshire East

- Facilitated Alcohol Support Groups and a satellite GP Shared Care service in the form of a prescribing clinic for clients.
- Conducted triage and risk assessments as well as referring clients. Devising and reviewing Care Plans/treatment pathways to meet the identified need of DIP clients.
- Completed Breach proceedings for non-attendance of individuals tested positive for substance use.
- Ensured completion of all forms relating to client in the form of care plans, TOPS, NDTMS, Activity Forms.

Oct 2010 – Mar 2011 Duty Assessor Worker & Womens' Group Co-Facilitator, Tower Hamlets DIP

- Achievements include establishing a Womens' Group in partnership with ISIS Womens' treatment services.
- Duty Assessor completed triage and risk assessments on a statutory and voluntary as a referral basis for clients using Class A and B drugs who wished to be signposted to specific treatment services in the borough.
- Maintaining contact on behalf of the co-workers when unavailable to meet with allocated clients – ensuring continuous co-ordination of client care.
- Completed Voluntary and Statutory Drug tests.
- Conducted DRR Assessments and delivered in report format and orally to District Judges and Lay Benches at Thames Magistrates Court.
- Liaised with Probation Officers, Treatment Providers, Mental Health Teams, GPs, Solicitors, Court Staff and Serco staff.

Feb 2010 - Oct 2010 RoB Co-ordinator Tower Hamlets DIP

- Significantly increased target figures of RoBs granted to clients in and out borough, subsequently increasing target figures of Clients engaging and reengaging in treatment as part of a "cell sweep" policy.
- Liaised and cultivated effective professional relationships with Clients, Key workers, GPs, Probation officers, with co-workers, Arrest Referral Workers, Through Care Key Workers, neighbouring DIP teams, Legal representatives, Solicitors, Probation, Mental Health Workers, Serco Gaelors, Police Liaison Officers, Security, Court Staff, Ushers, Prosecutors, Lay Benches, District Judges.
- Orally reported to Thames Magistrates court of verified client engagement and ongoing care plans. Appropriately interjected on occasions in court to advocate on behalf of self-representing clients in light of their confusion of the court proceedings as well as in the absence of legal advice.
- Supported Clients and family members of Clients during and after court proceedings.
- Discreetly sought potential Walk In Clients attending their first hearing, to sensitively enquire of potential support for class a drug use i.e. client focussed RoB package.

Sep 2009 - Feb 2010 Care Co-ordinator Lewisham DIP

Managed a case load of clients, under taking Triage and Risk assessments.
Devised and reviewed Care Plans/treatment pathways to meet the identified
need of DIP clients. Ensuring the provision of high quality advice, information,
counselling and support services support clients to effectively address their
problems and make constructive changes to their lives.

Dec 2012 – Jan 2013 Arrest Referral Worker, WDP Croydon DIP Sep – Oct 2012 Arrest Referral Worker, WDP Waltham Forest DIP Jun – Aug 2012 DIP Worker, Camden DIP Mar– Jun 2012 Link Worker, Penrose Fusion Lewisham DIP Oct 2011 – Feb 2012 Case Worker Blenheim CDP Project Jul – Oct 2011 Criminal Justice Worker, WDP Wandsworth CJIS Dec 2011 Arrest Referral Worker, Greenwich DIP Apr – Aug 2011Arrest Referral Worker, CRI Kensington & Chelsea DIP Feb – Sep 2009 Arrest Referral Worker - CRI Lambeth

- Arrest Referral I Worker based in Brixton, Kennington, Streatham, Lewisham, Chelsea, Hammersmith, Notting Hill, Battersea, Tooting, Holborn, Kentish Town, Hackney and Waltham Forest Police Stations. Completed Triage and Risk Assessments for clients arrested on trigger offences and tested positive for opiates and/or cocaine.
- Completed investigative searches for individuals who have not attended the Assessment process and prepared Breach proceedings for non-attendance of individuals tested positive.
- Undertaking Drug Rehabilitation Requirement Reports on behalf of Magistrates and Crown Courts. Accompanied clients to treatment centres in the borough.
- Assigned as Court Duty Worker at Greenwich, South Western, Hammersmith Magistrates Court applied for Restrictions on Bail on behalf of clients who wished to address drug and alcohol related issues As Prison Link Worker offered a resettlement service supporting released prisoners returning to the London borough of Lewisham.
- Compiling statistic research data on a daily, weekly and monthly basis for the Data Manager, DAT, and NTA.

Sep 2008 - Nov 2008 Substance Misuse Worker, St Mungo's, Lambeth

- Facilitating Womens' group sessions, Needle Exchange and Harm Clinic
- Completed Triage and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health and substance misuse issues
- Key working single homeless males in a hostel with mental health, ASB, drug and alcohol misuse issues
- Created and maintained care support plans
- Liaised with various agencies
- Monitored Health and safety aspects

Feb 2008 - Sep 2008 DIP & Open Access Worker Addaction, Dunstable

 Working within the Tier 2 service facilitating Needle Exchange and Harm Minimisation Conducting out Assessments and Reviews.

Apr 2002 - Jun 2004 CARAT Worker, RAPT

- Co-Facilitated Stimulant Support Groups Completed Triage and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health and substance misuse issues
- Key working single homeless males in a hostel with mental health, ASB, drug and alcohol misuse issues
- Created and maintained care support plans

Dec 2001 – Sep 2005 Honorary Volunteer, Key Worker, High Support Unit, St Georges' Hospital

- Co-Facilitated Methadone Prescribed Maintenance Support Groups.
- Completed Triage and Risk Assessments for clients with complex needs including mental health and substance misuse issues
- Key working single homeless males in a hostel with mental health, ASB, drug and alcohol misuse issues.